Worst. Heroes. Ever.
Suicide Squad is a action, adventure, fantasy film directed by David Ayer.
From DC Comics comes the Suicide Squad, an antihero team of incarcerated supervillains who act as deniable assets for the
United States government, undertaking high-risk black ops missions in exchange for commuted prison sentences.
Deadshot, played by Will Smith.
The Joker, played by Jared Leto.
Harley Quinn, played by Margot Robbie.
Rick Flag, played by Joel Kinnaman.
Amanda Waller, played by Viola Davis.
Boomerang, played by Jai Courtney.
Suicide Squad is a 2016 American superhero film based on the
supervillain/anti-hero team from DC Comics.
It is the third installment in the DC Extended Universe (DCEU).
The film was written and directed by David Ayer and stars an ensemble cast including Will Smith, Jared Leto, Margot Robbie, Joel Kinnaman,
Viola Davis, Jai Courtney, Jay Hernandez, Adewale Akinnuoye-Agbaje, Ike Barinholtz, Scott Eastwood, and Cara Delevingne.
In the film, a secret government agency led by Amanda Waller recruits imprisoned supervillains to execute
dangerous black ops missions and save the world from a powerful threat in exchange for reduced sentences.
By February 2009, a Suicide Squad film was in development at Warner Bros.
Ayer signed on to write and direct in September 2014, and
by October the casting process had begun.
Principal photography began in Toronto on April 13, 2015, with
additional filming in Chicago, and ended in August that year.
Suicide Squad premiered in New York City on August 1, 2016, and was
released in the United States on August 5 by Warner Bros.
It grossed $749 million on a budget of $175 million, becoming the
tenth-highest-grossing film of 2016, and received mixed reviews from critics.
Ayer himself disowned the film after its release, claiming that
extensive studio interference had ruined his vision.
It won an Academy Award for Best Makeup and Hairstyling at the 89th Academy Awards, making it the
only DCEU film to have won an Academy Award, and received numerous other accolades.
It was followed by a spin-off film, Birds of Prey (2020),
and a sequel, The Suicide Squad (2021).
The film explores themes of secret mission,
superhero, anti hero, villain, supervillain.